Claudio Villanueva

Address: 725 Amunategui Apt 1211, Santiago, Chile

Mobile: +56 9563 777 38 E-mail: claudioff@gmail.com

Nationality: Chilean

Personal Profile

I am passionate about software development, with around 12 years of experience building software and 8 years with iOS and Android apps. Besides considering myself as a mobile specialist I really enjoy learning new languages and technologies and I have a lot of ductility to work with all kind of software projects.

Achievements

- Have recently designed and migrated to Clean Architecture an iOS application with more than 500,000 users.
- Have designed a commercial TV detection application from scratch using image hashing algorithms.
- Have designed a mobile messaging system from scratch including iOS, Android, API and database.

Education

2003 – 2007 Bachelor in Computer Science – Engineering – University of Santiago

· Best bachelor's degree.

2011 – 2012 Japanese Language – Kudan Institute – Tokyo – Japan

Mid level, Working and daily life proficiency.

2008 - 2010 English classes with a particular teacher

• Fluent in English. Business level proficiency.

1995 – 1998 Mid Level Electronics Technician – Technical High School

Employment

August 2020 - Present - iOS developer - Transbank

- iOS apps development.
- IOS apps design & architecture.
- Team leading, junior developers mentoring and training.
- iOS apps CI/CD.

January 2020 - August 2020 - Software Engineer - ALMA Observatory

- Backend development and support to operation.
- Linux servers administration.
- · Continuous Integration and Delivery with Ansible, Jenkins and Artifactory.

March 2019 - December 2019 - iOS Developer - Tinet/WOM

- iOS apps development.
- IOS apps design & architecture.
- Team leading, junior developers mentoring and training.
- iOS apps CI/CD.
- Git repository management.

April 2017- January 2020 – Mobile developer R&D – Garapon Inc – Tokyo, Japan

- iOS & Android apps development and CI/CD.
- Research and development of computer vision based apps.
- API development.
- Linux apps development.
- Programming and optimization for big volume video data processing.

April 2013 – March 2017 – Software Developer – Pixtoome – Santiago, Chile

- iOS & Android apps design & development.
- API design & development.
- Database modeling.
- Web development.

December 2009 - March 2013 - Software Developer - Ubix - Santiago, Chile

- iOS, Android and Java Micro Edition apps design & development.
- API design & development.
- Database modeling.
- Web development.

July 2001 – November 2009 – Systems Administrator – Grau – Santiago, Chile

- Unix & Linux systems administration.
- Database administration.
- ERP systems Administration.

Skills

- Excellent knowledge of mobile apps related languages and SDK, including Swift, Java, Objective C, Kotlin, Android NDK and Apple frameworks. Releasing apps in stores. Debugging and profiling.
- Medium level knowledge of lower level languages such as C and C++. Experience programming high performance apps, and apps for embedded Linux devices.
- Good knowledge of Linux servers languages and software like PHP, Python, Java, Scala, Golang, Perl, Bash script, PostgreSQL, MySQL, ZeroMQ, RabbitMQ and Docker.
- Web development using Java frameworks, Javascript and CSS.
- Cloud resources management, AWS, Azure and Google.
- APIs development, microservices and containers deployment. Database modeling.
- Machine Learning models training.
- Continuous integration and delivery with Jenkins, Hudson and Ansible.
- RxSwift, Fastlane, Development Pods, and a diverse set of tools for iOS development.

References

Rene Ramirez

Ubix CEO +569 8837 2892

Javier Ergas

Pixtoome CEO +569 9871 5243

Portfolio, Repos and Demos

https://cvillanueva.github.io (To watch my done mobile apps)

https://github.com/cvillanueva (My repositories)

https://cvillanueva.github.io/aquila/ (Shoot'em up Game)

https://cvillanueva.github.io/Labyrintho/ (3D Maze adventure)